An asteroid ended the age of the dinosaurs 66 million years ago.
6600万年前，一颗小行星终结了恐龙时代。
Could something as catastrophic as that happen again?
像那样灾难性的事件会再次发生吗？
Asteroids are something astronomers closely track.
小行星是天文学家密切跟踪的对象。
Recently, the asteroid named 2024 YR4 made headlines for its tiny, but real, chance of colliding with Earth in 2032.
最近，一颗名为2024 YR4的小行星因其在2032年撞击地球的微小但真实的可能性而登上头条。
In February 2025, NASA increased the impact probability of this asteroid hitting us to 2.3%.
2025年2月，美国宇航局将这颗小行星撞击我们的概率提高到了2.3%。
Scientists have calculated that YR4 is between 40m and 90m in diameter.
科学家计算出YR4的直径在40米到90米之间。
It would have the power of a nuclear bomb if it was to hit Earth, causing severe damage if the impact was in a populated area.
如果它撞击地球，将具有核弹的威力，如果撞击发生在人口稠密地区，将造成严重破坏。
However, Dr Robert Massey of the Royal Astronomical Society urges calm.
然而，皇家天文学会的罗伯特·梅西博士呼吁保持冷静。
He said he is not "losing sleep over" the asteroid, but stresses that funding planetary defence and spotting potential threats is essential.
他说他并没有"为这颗小行星而瞎操心"，但强调为行星防御和发现潜在威胁提供资金是至关重要的。
So what are asteroids?
那么什么是小行星？
They are fragments of rock left over from the creation of the solar system 4.6 billion years ago.
它们是46亿年前太阳系形成时留下的岩石碎片。
They frequently orbit close to Earth pushed by the gravity of other planets, though it was only in the late 1900s that scientists were able to systematically track near-Earth objects and learn this.
在其他行星引力的推动下，它们经常在靠近地球的轨道上运行，然而直到20世纪末，科学家们才能够系统地跟踪近地天体并了解到这一点。
They found that asteroids of more than 40m across, that's large enough to destroy a city, cross the Earth's path within lunar distance several times a year.
他们发现，直径超过40米（足以摧毁一座城市）的小行星，每年会在地月距离内多次穿过地球的公转路径。
The chance of an asteroid being large enough to penetrate our atmosphere intact and destroy a city is likely to happen once in every hundred years.
一颗大到足以完整穿透大气层并摧毁一座城市的小行星撞击地球的可能性，大概每百年发生一次。
In 1908, an asteroid exploded over Siberia, injuring people and buildings across more than 500 square kilometres.
1908年，一颗小行星在西伯利亚上空爆炸，造成500多平方公里范围内的人员受伤和建筑物受损。
However, actual impacts aren't as common as near-misses.
然而，实际撞击并不像意外险情那样常见。
For example, the asteroid Apophis raised alarms after it was discovered in 2004 because it was estimated to be around the size of a cruise ship.
例如，小行星阿波菲斯在2004年被发现时就引起了警惕，因为它估计有一艘游轮那么大。
Even scarier, in 1994, the comet named Shoemaker-Levy 9 crashed into Jupiter, and, if it had hit Earth, all life would have been wiped out, just like the dinosaurs were.
更可怕的是，1994年，一颗名为舒梅克-列维9号的彗星撞上了木星，如果它撞击了地球，所有生命都会被消灭，就像恐龙一样。
So, it's safe to enjoy admiring the night sky because the chances of you being hit by an asteroid are very, very small, even if they're not zero.
所以，安心欣赏夜空是安全的，因为您被小行星击中的几率非常非常小，尽管并非为零。